(フカサク)こんなとこにおったんか。
So here you are.
(フカサク)ナルトちゃんよ たまに
１人でおらんようになるが➡
Naruto-chan, every once in
a while, you disappear.
どこへ行っとんじゃ？
Where do you go?
Well... nowhere in particular.
I just wander around...
(ナルト)いや 別に どこにも。
そのへん フラフラして…。
まあいい。
Well, no matter.
これから融合の練習を
やってみるけん➡
I want to practice merging starting now,
so come down here.
下に降りてきんさい。
大丈夫かな？
何がじゃ？
I wonder if they're okay.
What do you mean?
暁は 俺を狙ってんだろ？
The Akatsuki want me, right?
俺を探しに 木ノ葉に
来るんじゃないかと思ってさ。
I'm worried they will come looking
for me in the Leaf Village.
アホか！
What kind of fool are you?!
木ノ葉には 優秀な忍が
たくさん おるんじゃ！
The Hidden Leaf has
many fine ninjas!
今は よけいなことを考えず
やることをやる！
Stop your unnecessary musings and
concentrate on the work at hand!
なんか ありゃ 連絡ガエルが
知らせてくれるんじゃしな。
If anything happens,
the messenger frog will notify us.
よっしゃ！ じゃ 融合ってのを
やってみるってばよ！
All right!
Let's get on with this merging stuff!
Who could have imagined
such destruction?
《綱手 : ここまでの被害とは…》
what did I really lose that day?
ano hi honto ni ushinatta monotte nan dattakke
for the life of me I can't remember
tou ni wasureteshimatta yo
we slowly lost sight of each other in the twilight
yuugure de futari sukoshizutsu mienakunatteitte
and yet we're stuck here unable to go home
sore nanoni bokura kaerezu ni ita
weak, frail souls lost in the world
dokoka ni kowaresou na moroi kokoro
we act strong to hide their fragility
tsuyogaru kotoba de ootte kakushiteru
hide their fragility
ootte kakushiteru
so farewell, but even forced apart
sayonara aenakunattatte
our stories go on
bokura wa tsuzuki ga aru kara
even in a world without you, I run
kimi no inai sekai datte hashiru yo
to someday get past the pain
itsuka no itami mo koete
Mystery of Pain
(ダンゾウ)これで綱手の時代は終わる。
This spells the end of Tsunade's era.
だが 暁に九尾をくれてやる
わけにはいかぬからな。
However, we cannot allow
the Akatsuki to take Nine-Tails.
その可能性は排除した。
So I have eliminated that possibility.
我々は 上のほとぼりが冷めるまで
地下に潜る。
We will lay low underground
until the chaos dies down.
我々も援護したほうが
よいのでは？
Shouldn't we be assisting?
ダンゾウ様が上に立たれたとしても➡
Even if you should assume power,
it would be meaningless
木ノ葉と人がなくなったのでは
意味がありません。
if the citizens of
the Hidden Leaf are dead.
(ダンゾウ)姫も火影になった女だ。
The princess is now Hokage.
カツユの術を使用する以上
全滅はない。
As long as she can utilize
Katsuyu's jutsu,
the entire village will not perish.
それなりの死傷者は
出るであろうが➡
Certainly, there will be lives lost.
わしにとっては必要な犠牲だ。
But to me, that is a necessary sacrifice.
わしが火影になるためのな。
In order for me to become the Hokage...
((勝ちだぜ！))
I win!
Nothing tastes better than
a drink of sake after work.
((仕事明けの酒は最高だな))
(シモン)ダメだ… そっちは
何かわかったか トンボ？
No good.
Did you find out anything, Tonbo?
(トンボ)まだだ ペインにつながる
有力な手がかりは まだなしだ。
Not yet... Nothing promising that
is linked to Pain.
NO TRESPASSING
((リュウスイ : 今日の死体は軽いな。
Today's corpse is light.
(ユウダチ)長年のカンでわかる。
こりゃ 女だ。
It's a knack I got
from years of experience.
This one's a woman.
(リュウスイ)オレたちがいつも死体を運ぶ
この里で一番高い搭➡
The highest tower in the village
where we always deliver these bodies...
あそこが何か知ってるか？
You know what that's for?
(ユウダチ)だいたい この里では
搭ってのは➡
In a village like ours,
isn't it usually where the ashes
are enshrined?
骨を安置するためのもんだろ。
元々は 死者の供養や
報恩のために築かれた建造物だ。
They were originally built as
a memorial to honor the dead.
(リュウスイ)なら 何で死者の身内まで
立ち入り禁止になってる？
If that's the case,
why is it off-limits to the relatives
of the dead too?
(ユウダチ)さあな 知るかよ。
ヘヘヘ！
Like I care.
What? Stop acting arrogant.
なんだよ もったいつけんなよ！
実はな。
Actually... Rumor has it that
Lord Pain lives up there.
あそこに ペイン様が
いらっしゃるんじゃないかと➡
噂されている。
(ユウダチ)へえ そりゃすげえ！
Really? That's something.
って そんな訳ねえだろ。
(リュウスイ)噂だ。
But there's no way.
It's just a rumor. A rumor...
うわさ。
そんなことより 確認するぞ。
Never mind that. I'm gonna confirm it.
Just like you said. It's a woman.
お前の言うとおりだったな。 女だ。
(小南)ご苦労。
Good work.
Oh, Lady Angel...
ああ 天使様。
(早く次を運んできなさい))
Now quickly, bring the next one.
Inoichi is really amazing!
(トンボ)
いのいちさん やっぱ すげえよ！
コイツの半日を30秒足らずで
のぞいていく。
He can see half this guy's day
in a mere 30 seconds...
ついていくのが やっとだよ。
I can barely keep up!
(モズク)バカ野郎
しゃべるくらいなら➡
You fool!
If you have time to talk,
何か少しでも
ペインにつながるネタを探せ！
find something that
we can link to Pain!
Sorry for interrupting.
(シズネ)おじゃまします。 シズネです。
It's me, Shizune!
火影様の命で こちらに出向くよう
言い渡されました。
Lady Hokage ordered me
to come here!
(イビキ)そっちで 何かわかったか？
Did you learn anything on your side?
はい これから説明します。
Yes! I will explain immediately!
私の持っている情報と➡
The information I brought,
along with the data you possess,
こちらから出る情報を
照らし合わせて➡
will reveal Pain's identity!
ペインの正体をつかみます。
口寄せの術。
Summoning Jutsu!
(シズネ)ペインたちの体に いくつも
突き刺さっていた この黒い棒。
Each of the Pains had
black rods like this one
inserted in their bodies.
これが ヤツらの強さを解く
カギじゃないかと。
We believe this is the key
to explaining their power.
(いの)チャクラをお互い
送信しあってるってことかな？
Could it be that they use this to
transmit chakra to each other?
なんか 私たち一族の秘伝忍術に
近い能力ですね。
It's a similar ability to
our clan's Hidden Jutsu.
伝説の輪廻眼を持つ忍の祖。
The forefather of all ninja,
the Sage of the Six Paths,
possessed the legendary Rinnegan.
六道仙人と同じ眼を持つ存在。
Someone who possesses
the same eye...
そんなものが 本当にいるなら➡
If such a person really does exist,
どんな術が使えても
不思議ではないが。
then it wouldn't be a surprise,
no matter what jutsu he uses.
なんだ!?
What was that?!
It seems they have
shown up here as well.
どうやら ここにも
ヤツらが現れたようです。
私たちが食い止めます。
We will stop them.
風遁 風切りの術！
Wind Style: Wind Blade Jutsu!
雷遁 四柱しばり！
Lightning Style: Four-Pillar Trap!
Earth Style...
土遁 おとし蓋！
Buta Futa!
どうだ？
やったか？
Well? Did we do it?
(フカサク)よし 仙人モードの総決算
融合の修行 いくぞ！
All right! This completes
the steps to Sage Mode...
We'll now begin the merge training!
お おう！
Y-Yeah...!
要するに 俺の肩に
じいちゃん仙人が乗るんだな？
So basically, you're gonna get
on my shoulder, right?
さよう。
Correct.
ナルトちゃんが動いてるとき
わしが自然エネルギーを取り込む。
While you move,
I draw in Nature Energy.
そのコンビネーションを磨く修業じゃ。
うん。
This is a training to hone
that combination.
さあ 互いの呼吸を一つにして。
Now then, let us synchronize
our breathing.
おう！
Okay...
ぬ？ うわあ！
だ… 大丈夫か？ じいちゃん？
A-Are you okay, old frog?
S-Strange...
おかしいのう…。
もういっぺん やってみるけんの。
Let's try it once more.
仙法 両生の術。
Sage Art: Amphibian Jutsu!
うわ～っ！
It seems this is not possible.
どうやら 無理のようじゃな。
無理って!?
Not possible...?!
I suspect that the Nine-Tails
inside you is rejecting me.
おそらく
ナルトちゃんの中の九尾が➡
わしを拒絶して
弾き出してしまうんじゃろう。
んな バーカな！
No way!
じゃあ… じゃあ！
今での修業は何!?
Then what was all that training for?!
What are we gonna do?!
どうすんだってばよ！
ハハハ…。
なんだ!?
コイツ… 頭が増えてやがる！
What?!
This beast... is growing more heads!
Looks like a special type
of Summoning.
どうやら 特別な口寄せだな。
あれを相手にするより
術者を探しだすぞ！
Rather than fighting the beast,
let's find the one casting the jutsu!
どうしましょう？ シズネさん。
彼らなら…。
What should we do, Shizune-san?
As for them...
口寄せの術。
Summoning Jutsu!
Wh-What is that?!
(シズネ)な… なんなの!?
やはり…。
As I thought...
ここか。
It's here.
(カツユ)どうにか間に合いました。
It seems I made it in time.
カツユ様 助かりました。
Katsuyu-sama, thank you so much!
ヒィ！ って すみません カツユ様！
まだ 慣れなくて…。
Yikes! Forgive me, Katsuyu-sama,
I'm just not used to you yet.
いえいえ。
It's quite all right.
強力な口寄せです。
皆さん 気をつけてください。
They are powerful Summonings.
Everyone, please be careful.
(いのいち)間違いない…。
There's no mistake...
雨隠れの男の頭の中を
覗いたとき アイツを見た。
When I looked into the mind of
that fellow from the Hidden Rain...
I saw her.
だが どういうことだ？
なんです？
But how could this be?!
What is it?
あれは 死体だった。
She was a corpse!
《その死体が 今
口寄せの術を使う？
And that dead body...
is now using a Summoning Jutsu!
ペイン６人が使用する術は
一個体 一系統のみのはず！
It was thought each
of the six Pains
uses only one type of jutsu.
だとすると おかしい！
But something's wrong!
口寄せできるのは
あの検死体のペインだけだと➡
Fukasaku-sama said that
the only one who was able
to use Summoning was the Pain
we did the autopsy on!
フカサク様から聞いた。
どういうことなの？
口寄せができるペインは➡
What's going on?!
The Pain who was capable
of the Summoning Jutsu
すでに 自来也様が
倒したはずなのに…》
has already been killed
by Jiraiya-sama!
いのいちさん
もう少し詳しく話を！
Inoichi-san! Please give me more details.
何かわかるかもしれません。
I might be able to figure this out!
しかし この状態では…。
But in our current situation...
ここは 俺と暗部に任せて
別の場所へ。
Leave this place to
the Anbu Black Ops and me.
Get to safety!
イビキ！
さぁ 早く！ いのいちさん！
Ibiki...!
Let's hurry, Inoichi-san!
私たちで
ペインの正体を暴くんです！
We must uncover
Pain's true identity!
とりあえず
暗号部のところへ行きます！
We'll head to the Cipher Division
for the time being.
いのいちさんの術のサポートを兼ねて
いのさんも同行させてください。
Have Ino-san accompany us
to assist your jutsu.
わかった。
Got it...
《俺だ！ いの。 よく聞け。
It's me, Ino. Listen carefully.
暗号部のところへ移動するぞ！》
We are moving to the Cipher Division.
いくぞ!!
Let's go!
お前の相手は 俺たちだ。
We shall be your opponents!
少しは しゃべってみたらどうだ？
張り合いがないだろう。
Why don't you speak?!
You're no fun at all.
お前がその気なら➡
Humph! If that's your attitude,
自らしゃべりたくなるように
してやろう。
then I shall make you want to speak!
犬コロは 我らが！
We'll deal with the dog!
コンビネーションＢ！
承知！
Combination B!
Right.
風遁 風切りの術！
Wind Style!
Wind Blade Jutsu!
雷遁 四柱しばり！
Lightning Style!
Four-Pillar Trap!
土遁 粘土おとし！
Earth Style, Mud Fall!
雷遁 十六柱しばり！
Lightning Style!
Sixteen-Pillar Trap!
火遁 素焼の術！
Fire Style!
Biscuit Firing Jutsu!
口寄せ 哀暗冥電！
Summoning!
Iron Maiden!
口寄せ 拷問部屋！
Summoning...
Torture Chamber!
口を割らせてやる。
I'll loosen your mouth.
お前たちの秘密を
しゃべってもらう。
And you'll tell us... your secrets.
ペイン…。
Pain... What a nice name.
いい名だ。
痛みこそが
最も信用できるコミュニケーションだ。
Pain is the most reliable form
of communication.
お前の痛みを 俺にも感じさせろ。
Let me feel your pain too...
そうだ 痛みは嘘をつかない。
Yes... Pain does not lie.
痛みのなかで 俺たちは平等だ。
Through pain, we are equals...
痛みを共有し➡
I will share your pain.
同じ痛みのなかで お前を知る。
And I will get to know you
through pain.
さあ 見せてみろ。
Now show me... the real you.
本当のお前を。
さあ！
Now...
《コイツ 痛みなど感じていない。
This one... isn't feeling any pain.
それに この冷たさ。
And... this cold...
まさに死体…》
It's like... a dead body!
お前の語る痛みなど
どれほどのもの。
Just what is this pain you speak of?
真の痛みが
お前ごときに わかるはずもない。
The likes of you would
never understand true pain.
口寄せの術！
Summoning Jutsu!
ぐお～！ ぐっ…。
口寄せの術！
Summoning Jutsu!
ありえん。
Impossible...!
yesterday, I cut my hair a little
kinou sukoshi kami wo kitta
if I don't say it, I'm sure
iwanakareba kitto
nobody will realise, I guess
daremo kizukanai darou kedo
for a long time
nankagetsu ka bun no
I looked
watashi ga yuka ni
at what fell down on the floor
okkochita no wo mita
I closed my eyes
me wo tojite
and I could hear the sound of rain
kikoete kita ame no oto
even from above the clouds, I'm sure
kumo no ue demo kitto
take out a pair of scissors
hasami mochidashite
we're waiting for the light
hikari wo matteiru
bicycle, bicycle, bicycle, bicycle, bicycle
jitensha jitensha jitensha jitensha jitensha
pedal, pedal, pedal, pedal
koide koide koide koide
pedal, and come on
koideiku yo
right now, right now, right now, right now, right now
imasugu imasugu imasugu imasugu imasugu
bicycle, bicycle
jitensha jitensha
pedal
koide
let's go to see him
ano hito ni ai ni yukou
bicycle, bicycle, bicycle, bicycle, bicycle
jitensha jitensha jitensha jitensha jitensha
pedal, pedal, pedal
koide koide koide
let's go to see him
ano hito ni ai ni yukou
ずいぶん書類たまったな。
Next Episode
No, Konohamaru-kun! Why didn't you run?!
もう！ これじゃ
今日のデートも おあずけね。
I made a promise, long ago...
って…
そんな相手 いないでしょう！
What?
That someday, I would fight Naruto nii-chan
over the title of Hokage!
He is my rival!
仕事しよ。
So I'm not choosing an escape route!
忍者登録書…。
Because Naruto nii-chan won't be waiting at the end of such a path!
ずいぶん更新されてないわねぇ。
Next time on Naruto Shippuden: "Surname is Sarutobi! Given Name, Konohamaru!"
Surname is Sarutobi! Given Name, Konohamaru!
うわあ！ みんな若～い！
これ ルーキー９時代の写真じゃない。
Remember that!
たった数年で ホント➡
みんな立派になったわね。
The documents are piling up.
あっ！
また… ったく あの子は！
Oh well, I have to cancel tonight's date.
Yeah right...
I don't even have a date!
ゲンゾウさんに
撮り直してもらわなくちゃ。
Better get back to work...
あっ！
Ninja Registration Form...
NINJA REGISTRATION FORM
変なことばっかり真似すんな！
A lot of this hasn't been updated.
Oh, wow!
They're all so young.
あひ～っ！
These are photos from
their Rookie Nine days.
And look at them now,
in just a few short years.
ったく これじゃ
飲んでなくても酔っちまう。
Huh?!
で 何かわかったのか？
My goodness... That child...
(ラハール)点と点が
少しずつ線になってきた。
I have to ask Kenzo to retake it.
お前のおかげだ。 ドラン…。
Huh?!
メスト。
Quit copying such silly things!